George Dillon Papers
George Dillon Papers
1862-1982
Dillon, George, 1906-1968.
13 linear ft.
The papers of the American poet include correspondence (1862-1973), family as well as that related to his editorship of Poetry magazine; minutes of the Modern Poetry Association (1950-1962); family diaries, financial papers, photographs, scrapbooks, and manuscripts that include material on a translation of "Les Fleurs du Mal" by Baudelaire, produced in collaboration with Edna St. Vincent Millay, and other translations of French authors, including Giraudoux, Prévert, and Ronsard. Correspondents include Helen S. Arthur, Robert Ballou, Morris Bishop, Eugen Boissevain, Amy Bonner, Inez Boulton, Augustine Bowe, Jean Burden, Witter Bynner, Gladys Campbell, Margaret Carpenter, Hayden Carruth, John Ciardi, Jean Cocteau, Malcolm Cowley, James Daly, Peter DeVries, Benjamin Huebsch, Nicholas Joost, Hugh Kenner, James Laughlin, Vachel Lindsay, Katinka Loeser, Je ssica MacDonald, Archibald MacLeish, Marcia Lee Masters, Harry Meacham, Arthur Meeker, Paul Mellon, William Meredith, Edna St. Vincent Millay, Bonner Mitchell, Adrienne Monnier, Harriet Monroe, Marianne Moore, Gilbert Neiman, John Nerber, Louise Townsend Nicholl, John F. Nims, Sterling North, Gil Orlovitz, Henry Rago, Jean Rivier, Karl Jay Shapiro, William Jay Smith, Florence Stearns, Marion Strobel, Allen Tate, Jean Starr Untermeyer, Monroe Wheeler, and Morton Zabel.
148942
Biographical History
George Dillon (1906-1968) was an American poet and editor.
Born in Jacksonville, Florida, Dillon's parents moved around frequently when he was a child and he lived in Kentucky, Ohio, and Missouri, before moving to Chicago after high school. As a student at the University of Chicago, Dillon began to write and edit poetry.
Dillon's first poetry collection, Boy in the Wind, appeared when he was barely twenty-one, yet the critic for the Dial stated: "There is no timidity of evasion, no suggestion of frailty or wavering. His lines have always the assurance of authority, the finality of complete mastery." Louis Untermeyer, in the Saturday Review of Literature, wrote: "His pages...tempt one to cast aside criticism for scarcely reserved enthusiasm." Untermeyer decided that Dillon had not fulfilled his earlier promise, however he was omitted from subsequent editions.
Of his second volume, The Flowering Stone - which won the Pulitzer Prize - Babette Deutsch, the critic for the New York Herald Tribune Books, wrote that though Dillon had been attentive to the lessons of more established poets, "no poet save himself can have brought him to the source of his poetry, or unsealed that bright fountain to our refreshment and joy. Only a searching mind and an alert, sensitive body could have combined to produce poetry of this calibre." Dillon translated poems by Ronsard, Aragon, Eluard, and Michaux, all of which were published in Poetry. Indeed, he is now chiefly remembered for these, since he failed to develop the promise shown in his first volumes. Now chiefly remembered for his Baudelaire and Racine translations, Dillon failed to add to his reputation after his second volume of poetry. [From World Authors 1900-1950 (1996)]
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The George Dillon Papers comprise Correspondence-subject files, Writings and Memorabilia. Spanning the years 1862 to 1982, the collection illuminates both the family relationships and the creative work of the Pulitzer Prize-winning poet (The Flowering Stone, 1931) and translator of the works of such luminaries of French belles-lettres as Baudelaire, Giraudoux, Racine and Ronsard.
Among the Correspondence-subject files are both personal and business letters, the latter chiefly in connection with Dillon's tenure with Poetry, first as associate editor (1925-27) during his undergraduate years at the University of Chicago, and later as successor to its founder and editor, Harriet Monroe. The correspondence which is of greatest depth and duration includes letters from Amy Bonner, Eugen Boissevain, Inez Boulton, Jeanne Daladier, Alix Du Poy Daniel, Carl Hillerns, Ben Huebsch, Nicholas Joost, Marcia Lee Masters (Schmid), Arthur Meeker, Lila Michaelides, Edna St. Vincent Millay, John Nerber, Henry Rago, Karl Shapiro, Florence Dickinson Stearns, Marion Strobel, Geraldine Udell and Jean Starr Untermeyer. Also in the collection is an extensive assortment of family correspondence including letters of Adah Hill and William S. Dillon (parents) to George, other family members, and friends. Among the other family correspondents are Alice Sinclair Hill and Alice Baur Hodges, and various members of the Dillon and Hill families.
The Writings (Boxes 12-14) encompass articles, books, and poetry in printed and/or manuscript form. Book manuscripts include typescript drafts and revisions of Dillon's translations of Baudelaire (Flowers of Evil) and Racine (Three Plays of Racine), together with two unpublished translations: Giraudoux's Le Guerre de Trois n'aura pas Lieu ("No War in Troy") and Ronsard's sonnets and lyrics, "Four Seasons of Love." Also among Dillon's poetry translations is the work of Jean Cocteau, Jacques Prévert, and Jules Supervielle.
Boxes 15-16 of the Memorabilia have been categorized as either family material or George Dillon's personal mementos. Among the family memorabilia is genealogical material relating to the Dillon, Hill, and Sinclair families as well as financial, legal and miscellaneous documents and clippings. George Dillon's personal memorabilia has been arranged chronologically, from childhood through his academic career, his military assignment, and his activities from 1945 until his death in 1968. Also categorized under personal memorabilia is financial, legal and printed material, the latter including a number of theater programs and musical scores. Boxes 17-19 are comprised of photographs and scrapbooks relating to George Dillon and other family members. Eleven oversized packages contain diaries of Alice Sinclair Hill, drawings by George Dillon as well as scrapbooks of clippings and theatrical memorabilia.
Arrangement of the Collection
Alphabetical by type or topic.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Poetry; Arthur, Helen S.; Ballou, Robert O. (Robert Oleson), 1892-1977.; Baudelaire, Charles, 1821-1867. -- Fleurs du mal -- Translations.; Bishop, Morris, 1893-1973.; Boissevain, Eugen, -1949.; Bonner, Amy.; Boulton, Inez.; Bowe, Augustine Joseph, 1892-1966.; Burden, Jean.; Bynner, Witter, 1881-1968.; Campbell, Gladys.; Carpenter, Margaret Haley.; Carruth, Hayden, 1921-2008.; Ciardi, John, 1916-1986.; Cocteau, Jean, 1889-1963.; Cowley, Malcolm, 1898-1989.; Daly, James Joseph, 1901-; De Vries, Peter, 1910-1993.; Dillon, George, 1906-1968.; Giraudoux, Jean, 1882-1944. -- Guerre de Troie n'aura pas lieu -- Translations.; Huebsch, B. W. (Benjamin W.), 1876-1964.; Joost, Nicholas.; Kenner, Hugh.; Laughlin, James, 1914-1997.; Lindsay, Vachel, 1879-1931.; Loeser, Katinka.; MacDonald, Jessica North, 1894-; MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-1982.; Masters, Marcia Lee.; Meacham, Harry M. (Harry Monroe), 1901-1975.; Meeker, Arthur, 1902-1971.; Mellon, Paul.; Meredith, William, 1919-2007.; Millay, Edna St. Vincent, 1892-1950.; Mitchell, Bonner.; Monnier, Adrienne.; Monroe, Harriet, 1860-1936.; Moore, Marianne, 1887-1972.; Neiman, Gilbert.; Nerber, John.; Nicholl, Louise Townsend.; Nims, John Frederick, 1913-1999.; North, Sterling, 1906-1974.; Orlovitz, Gil, 1918-1973.; Prévert, Jacques, 1900-1977 -- Translations.; Rago, Henry, 1915-1969.; Rivier, Jean, 1896-1987.; Ronsard, Pierre de, 1524-1585.; Shapiro, Karl, 1913-2000.; Smith, William Jay, 1918-2015.; Stearns, Florence (Dickinson), 1883-; Strobel, Marion, 1895-; Tate, Allen, 1899-1979.; Untermeyer, Jean Starr, 1886-1970.; Wheeler, Monroe, 1899-1988.; Zabel, Morton Dauwen, 1901-1964.; Modern Poetry Association.; Poetry (Chicago); American literature -- 20th century.; American poetry -- 20th century.; French literature -- Translations into English.; Periodical editors -- United States.; Poetry, Modern -- 20th century.; Poets, American.; Diaries.; Genealogies (histories); Manuscripts for publication.; Photographs.; Programs (documents); Scrapbooks.; Editors.; Poets.; Translators.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of George Dillon and Alice Hodges.
Inventory
- Correspondence-subject files
  - Biographical material (Box 1)
  - A (Box 1)
  - Alsberg, Henry G., 1938 (Box 1)
  - Armour, Alexander W., 1940-1954; undated (Box 1)
  - Arthur, Helen S., 1938; 1939 (Box 1)
  - Avrett, Robert, 1960 (Box 1)
  - B (Box 1)
  - Baker, Aaron W., 1862; 1863 (Box 1)
  - Ballou, Robert Oleson, 1961; 1966-1968 (Box 1)
  - Bauer, Robert, 1957-1961 (Box 1)
  - Baur, Emil, 1906-1910; 1932 (Box 1)
  - Baur, George A., 1946-1948; undated (Box 1)
  - Baur, Nannie Hill, 1906-1912; 1923-1966,; undated; 11 folders (Box 1)
  - Beach, Sylvia, See Princeton University Library.
  - Bell, Charles Greenleaf, 1957-1962 (Box 2)
  - Bertele, Rene, 1960 (Box 2)
  - Bird, Dorothy Maywood, 1967 (Box 2)
  - Bishop, Morris, 1961; 1962,; 1971 (Box 2)
  - Boissevain, Eugen, 1928; 1930,; 1937-1939,; undated (Box 2)
  - Bonner, Amy, 1937-1940; 1949,; 1953-1957,; undated (Box 2)
  - Boulton, Inez, 1941; 1942,; 1949-1952,; 1957,; undated (Box 2)
  - Boulton, Rudyerd (and Louise Rehm), 1959-1963 (Box 2)
  - Bowe, Augustine Joseph (and Julia), 1945; 1949,; 1950,; 1955,; 1968 (Box 2)
  - Boynton, Percy H., 1938 (Box 2)
  - Bradley, Jenny, 1973; 1975,; 1982 (Box 2)
  - Bridges, Betsy Eden, 1939; 1962-1966,; 1972,; 1973 (Box 2)
  - Brittin, Norman A., 1964; 1973-1980 (Box 2)
  - Brown, John L., 1945; 1946 (Box 2)
  - Burden, Jean, 1951-1968; undated; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Bynner, Witter, 1947; 1949,; 1961,; 1962 (Box 2)
  - C (Box 2)
  - Cairns, Huntington, 1946 (Box 2)
  - Campbell, Gladys, 1938; 1949-1968,; undated; 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Campbell, Kathleen Winifred, 1950; 1957,; 1958,; 1961 (Box 2)
  - Cannon, Isabelle C., 1940; 1944,; 1951,; undated (Box 2)
  - Carpenter, Margaret Haley, 1958-1961; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Carpenter, Margaret Haley, 1962-1982; undated; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Carruth, Hayden, 1949; undated (Box 3)
  - Castle, Marian, 1946; 1956 (Box 3)
  - Catel, Jean, 1945?; 1946 (Box 3)
  - Chapin, Katherine Garrison, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Ciardi, John, 1946 (Box 3)
  - Clark, Alexander Frederick Bruce, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Clemens, Cyril, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Cocteau, Jean, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Coignard, James, 1945; 1974 (Box 3)
  - Coleman, Elliott, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Colony, Horatio, 1961; 1966 (Box 3)
  - Covington, Annette, 1935 (Box 3)
  - Cowley, Malcolm, 1946 (Box 3)
  - Daladier, Jeanne, 1935-1941; undated; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Daly, James Joseph, 1937; 1938,; 1941 (Box 3)
  - de Daura, Louise, 1930; 1937-1938,; undated (Box 3)
  - Davidson, Gustav, 1957; 1959,; 1960 (Box 3)
  - De Vries, Peter, 1941-1945; 1950,; 1959,; 1961 (Box 3)
  - Dietz, Frieda Meredith, 1939 (Box 3)
  - Dillon, B. F., 1906; 1910,; undated (Box 3)
  - Dillon, B. F. Jr. (Frank), 1910; 1942-1944 (Box 3)
  - Dillon, Diane, 1965; 1968 (Box 3)
  - Dillon, James Thomas, 1949; 1951 (Box 3)
  - Dillon, Walter B., 1945-1954; 1964 (Box 3)
  - Dillon, William S. and Adah Hill, 1905-1913; 1930-1935,; 1883,; 1897,; 1927; 7 folders of 36 (Box 3)
  - Dillon, William S. and Adah Hill, 1936-July 1944; 16 folders of 36 (Box 4)
  - Dillon, William S. and Adah Hill, Aug. 1944-1962; undated; 13 folders of 36 (Box 5)
  - Ditmars, Ann, 1906; 1937-1941,; 1949,; 1953,; 1955,; undated (Box 6)
  - Drew, Fraser Bragg, 1950; 1961 (Box 6)
  - Du Poy Daniel, Alix, 1935-1938; 1949-1967; 4 folders (Box 6)
  - E (Box 6)
  - Elinor Wylie Poetry Fellowship, 1938 (Box 6)
  - Elton, George, 1969 (Box 6)
  - Elton, William R., 1949 (Box 6)
  - Emery, Ola Bland, 1963; 1964,; 1966 (Box 6)
  - English, Maurice, 1966-1975; undated (Box 6)
  - F (Box 6)
  - Flaccus, Kimball, 1955 (Box 6)
  - Flint, Edith Foster, 1927; 1931,; 1934,; 1944,; 1949 (Box 6)
  - Friar, Kimon, 1937; 1962 (Box 6)
  - Frost, Elizabeth Hollister, 1929 (Box 6)
  - Frost, Robert, 1937 (Box 6)
  - G (Box 6)
  - Galland, Georgette, 1962-1964; undated (Box 6)
  - Giroux, Robert, 1947 (Box 6)
  - Gordon, Alvin J., 1946 (Box 6)
  - Greene, Luther, 1948; 1949 (Box 6)
  - Gresham, Hattie Belle, 1937; 1952,; undated (Box 6)
  - H (Box 6)
  - Hall, Gordon Langley, 1966; undated (Box 6)
  - Hanna, Alfred Jackson, 1942 (Box 6)
  - Harcourt, Brace, and Company, 1946 (Box 6)
  - Harper & Row, Publishers, 1962; 1963,; 1967 (Box 6)
  - Hayakawa, Margedant Peters, See Peters, Margedant.
  - Hill, Alice Sinclair, 1906-1914; 1927,; 1931,; undated (Box 6)
  - Hill, George W., 1875; 1885,; 1907-1911,; 1941,; undated (Box 6)
  - Hill, Marshall A., 1906; 1907,; 1931-1937 (Box 6)
  - Hill, Tom E., 1941-1963; 1967,; 1968,; undated (Box 6)
  - Hillerns, Carl, 1937-1941; 1947,; 1951-1961,; undated; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Hodges, Alice Baur, 1910; 1926,; 1939-1941,; 1949-1960,; 1927; George's cousin; nickname "Missy"; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Hodges, Alice Baur, 1961-1977; 1982,; undated; George's cousin; nickname "Missy"; 7 folders (Box 7)
  - Hodges, Alice Baur, "Lila", with editorial comment by George Dillon; 1 folder (Box 7)
  - Hoffman, Minna Bonner, 1956; 1958 (Box 7)
  - Huebsch, Ben, 1952-1964; undated (Box 7)
  - Indiana University Press, 1959; 1961,; 1973 (Box 7)
  - J (Box 7)
  - Jacoby, Grover, 1967; 1968 (Box 7)
  - James, Bertha Ten Eyck, 1937; 1945,; 1961 (Box 7)
  - Joost, Nicholas, 1953-1962 (Box 7)
  - K (Box 7)
  - Kenner, Hugh, 1961 (Box 7)
  - L (Box 7)
  - Lacoste, Maurice, 1947 (Box 7)
  - Laughlin, James, 1946; 1948,; undated (Box 7)
  - Lea, Thomas C., 1949-1955; 1961 (Box 7)
  - Le Breton, Maurice, 1946; 1961 (Box 7)
  - Lee, Lawrence, 1938; 1961 (Box 7)
  - Lengyel, Cornel Adam, 1968 (Box 7)
  - Lesemann, Maurice, 1961; 1962 (Box 7)
  - Lieberman, Elias, 1937; 1938 (Box 7)
  - Lindsay, Vachel, 1914 (Box 7)
  - Little, Virginia Skilling, 1941; 1948,; undated (Box 7)
  - Loeser, Katinka, 1945; 1947,; undated (Box 7)
  - Lovett, Robert Morss, 1934; 1937 (Box 7)
  - Lowe, Robert Liddell, 1959 (Box 7)
  - M (Box 7)
  - MacDonald, Jessica Nelson (North), 1937; 1950,; 1953,; 1958,; 1961,; 1968 (Box 7)
  - Macdougall, Allan Ross, 1951 (Box 7)
  - MacLeish, Archibald, 1937; 1942,; 1944-1945 (Box 7)
  - Malone, Ted, 1939 (Box 7)
  - Manderfeld, Viola, 1957-1961; undated (Box 7)
  - Masters, Marcia Lee, 1942; 1946,; 1955,; 1961,; 1967-1968,; undated (Box 7)
  - Meacham, Harry M., 1954-1962; 1967-1968 (Box 8)
  - Meeker, Arthur, 1934-1939; 1950-1961,; 1965-1968 (Box 8)
  - Mellon, Paul, 1949; 1961 (Box 8)
  - Meredith, William, 1969 (Box 8)
  - Michaelides, Lila, 1934-1940 (Box 8)
  - Michaux, Henri, 1943? (Box 8)
  - Milford, Nancy, 1973-1979 (Box 8)
  - Millay, Edna St. Vincent, 1928-1940; 1952,; 1957-1962,; undated; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Millay, Norma, 1962; 1968 (Box 8)
  - Miller, Cecilia Parsons, 1960 (Box 8)
  - Mitchell, Joan, 1935; 1966,; 1967,; undated (Box 8)
  - Mitgang, Herbert, 1965-1966 (Box 8)
  - Modern Poetry Association, 1950-1962; undated (Box 8)
  - Molloy, Paul, 1965 (Box 8)
  - Monnier, Adrienne, 1946; 1965,; 1973 (Box 8)
  - Monroe, Harriet, 1927-1938; undated (Box 8)
  - Monroe, William Stanton, 1946 (Box 8)
  - Moore, Marianne, 1961; 1966 (Box 8)
  - Morot-Sir, Edouard, 1961 (Box 8)
  - N (Box 8)
  - Neiman, Gilbert, 1959-1962 (Box 8)
  - Nerber, John, 1945-1962; 1967,; undated; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Nicholl, Louise Townsend, 1959-1960 (Box 8)
  - Nims, John Frederick, 1942; 1946,; 1950,; 1960 (Box 8)
  - North, Sterling, 1955 (Box 8)
  - O (Box 8)
  - O'Connor, William Van, 1961 (Box 8)
  - Orlovitz, Gil, 1955 (Box 8)
  - P (Box 8)
  - Parker, Elinor Milnor, 1962 (Box 8)
  - Pearson, Norman Holmes, 1962 (Box 8)
  - Peters, Margedant, 1946; 1950,; 1961 (Box 8)
  - Pocket Books, Inc., 1962-1963 (Box 8)
  - Poetry, a Magazine of Verse, 1940; 1941,; 1949,; 1950,; 1954-1969,; undated; 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Pratt, Edwin John, 1962 (Box 8)
  - Princeton University Library, 1973; 1976 (Box 8)
  - Princeton University Press, 1975 (Box 8)
  - R (Box 9)
  - Rago, Henry, See Poetry, a Magazine of Verse.
  - Rivier, Jean, 1947; 1961,; 1963,; 1970,; 1974,; 1975 (Box 9)
  - Roberts, Ruby Altizer, 1953-1956 (Box 9)
  - Ross, David, 1939; 1961 (Box 9)
  - S (Box 9)
  - Schultz, Hanns Stefan, 1961 (Box 9)
  - Seiffert, Marjorie Allen, 1961 (Box 9)
  - Seward, William Ward, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Shapiro, Karl Jay, 1946-1954; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Siebel, Julia, 1957-1961 (Box 9)
  - Simms, Mary, 1936-1939 (Box 9)
  - Smith, William Jay, 1946 (Box 9)
  - Solomont, Susan, 1967 (Box 9)
  - Stearns, Florence (Dickinson), 1938; 1939,; 1943,; 1952-1961,; undated; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Stephan, Ruth, 1944; 1960,; 1964 (Box 9)
  - Stevenson, Ellen (Mrs. Adlai), 1955 (Box 9)
  - Strobel, Marion, 1936; 1937,; 1949-1965,; undated; 3 folders (Box 9)
  - Strull, Harold, 1945-1947; 1961 (Box 9)
  - Sullivan, A. M., 1961 (Box 9)
  - Supervielle, Jules, 1960; 1961 (Box 9)
  - Sussman, Nan Bright, 1961 (Box 9)
  - T (Box 9)
  - Takacs, Stefan, 1933 (Box 9)
  - Tate, Allen, 1946 (Box 9)
  - Temple University Press, See English, Maurice.
  - Trigg, Emma Gray (White), 1937; 1956,; 1958,; 1961,; 1968,; undated (Box 9)
  - Tunstall, Virginia Hunter Lyne, 1950; 1955,; 1961 (Box 9)
  - Turbyfill, Mark, 1950; 1965 (Box 9)
  - U (Box 9)
  - Udell, Geraldine, 1939-1967; undated; 2 folders (Box 9)
  - University of Chicago Press, 1946; 1949,; 1957-1967 (Box 10)
  - Untermeyer, Jean Starr, 1965-1968 (Box 10)
  - Valsa, M., 1938; 1957 (Box 10)
  - Viking Press, 1932; 1938,; 1951 (Box 10)
  - W (Box 10)
  - Wescott, G. L., undated (Box 10)
  - Wheeler, Monroe, 1960 (Box 10)
  - Whiteley, Mary N. S., undated (Box 10)
  - Wilder, Isabel, 1936 (Box 10)
  - Wood, Audrey, 1939 (Box 10)
  - Y (Box 10)
  - Zabel, Morton Dauwen, 1936-1937 (Box 10)
  - Telegrams, 1906; 1910,; 1912,; undated (Box 10)
  - Unidentified, 3 folders (Box 10)
- Writings
  - Articles
    - "Modern Poetry," Proceedings of Conference on Contemporary Culture, Purdue University, undated (Box 11)
    - "A Note on the Obvious," A Casebook on Ezra Pound, 1959 (Box 11)
    - "Style and the Many-headed Beast", June 1955; typescript manuscript with corrections (Box 11)
  - Books
    - Translations
      - Baudelaire, Charles. Flowers of Evil, typescript ms. (Box 11)
      - Baudelaire, Charles. Flowers of Evil, 1962; undated; revisions (Box 11)
      - Three Plays of Racine, first comments from teachers, 1961; excerpts from letters (Box 11)
      - Three Plays of Racine, "Notes on Racine and French Classicism", undated (Box 11)
      - Three Plays of Racine, introductory notes - typescript drafts with holograph corrections; 3 folders (Box 11)
      - Three Plays of Racine, Introduction, typescript drafts with holograph corrections; 2 folders (Box 11)
      - Racine, Jean Baptiste. Andromaque (Box 11)
      - "Andromache", holograph draft (Box 11)
      - "Andromache", typescript draft with holograph corrections; 2 folders (Box 11)
      - Racine, Jean Baptiste. Britannicus (Box 11)
      - "Britannicus", holograph draft (Box 11)
      - "Britannicus", typescript draft with holograph corrections; 2 folders (Box 11)
      - "Britannicus", typescript draft with holograph corrections; 2 folders (Box 12)
      - Racine, Jean Baptiste. Phedre (Box 12)
      - "Phaedra", typescript draft with holograph corrections; 3 folders (Box 12)
    - Translations, unpublished
      - Giraudoux, Jean. La Guerre de Trois n'aura pas Lieu (Box 12)
      - Giraudoux, Jean. "No War in Troy", typescript draft with holograph corrections; 2 folders (Box 12)
      - Ronsard, Pierre de. "Four Seasons of Love", typescript draft; 5 folders (Box 12)
      - Ronsard, Pierre de. "Four Seasons of Love", typescript draft; 1 folder (Box 13)
  - Poetry
    - Miscellaneous poems, typescript and holograph manuscripts (Box 13)
  - Poetry translations
    - Cocteau, Jean. "L'Adieu aux Fusiliers Marins" (Box 13)
    - Prevert, Jacques. "Barbara" (Box 13)
    - Prevert, Jacques. "Je Suis Comme Je Suis" (Box 13)
    - Prevert, Jacques. "This Love" (Box 13)
    - Supervielle, Jules. "Homage to Life" (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous authors (Box 13)
    - Unidentified (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous notes on translation (Box 13)
  - Miscellany
    - "George Dillon Presents the Library", May 1938; transcript of address delivered at the dedication of the Harriet Monroe Library of Modern Poetry, printed in the Courier (Box 13)
    - Reader's reports, May 27, 1967 (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous fragments (Box 13)
    - Notes (miscellaneous) (Box 13)
  - Galleys
    - Baudelaire, Charles. Flowers of Evil, 4 folders (Box 14)
    - Three Plays of Racine (Box 14)
- Memorabilia
  - Family
    - Certificate of membership in the Florida Society of the Sons of the American Revolution, B.F. Dillon, July 8, 1908 (Oversize 4)
    - Diaries, Alice Sinclair Hill, 1906 (Oversize 2)
    - Genealogical material, Dillon family (Box 15)
    - Genealogical material, Hill family (Box 15)
    - Genealogical material, Sinclair family (Box 15)
    - Genealogical material, miscellaneous (Box 15)
    - Financial material, William S. and Adah Hill Dillon, 4 folders (Box 15)
    - Legal material
      - Dillon, Adah Hill, Estate of (Box 15)
      - Dillon, William S., Estate of (Box 15)
      - Hill, Alice S., Estate of (Box 15)
      - Hill, George W., Estate of (Box 15)
      - Patent information (Box 15)
    - Cemetery and monuments (Box 15)
    - Dillon, Adah Hill, memorial book (Box 15)
    - Dillon, Adah Hill, recitation book (Box 15)
    - Dillon, Adah Hill, scrapbook of postcards from William S. Dillon (Box 16)
    - Dillon, William S. (Box 16)
    - Dillon, William S. and Adah Hill, 30th anniversary book of William and Jennie Dillon, 1938 (Box 16)
    - Dillon, William S. and Adah Hill, wedding book and dishes, 1906 (Box 16)
    - House plans (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous, 2 folders (Box 17)
    - Clippings, circa 1890s-1960 (Box 17)
  - George Dillon
    - Childhood-academia, notebooks (Box 17)
    - Childhood-academia, miscellaneous (Box 17)
    - Chinese robes, George Dillon from Harriet Monroe, 2 items (Oversize 3)
    - The Echo, 1923; original drawings by George Dillon, Webster High School (Oversize 4)
    - Military
      - Radio engineering section - "com. zone radio circuits" (Box 17)
      - Radio engineering section - notebook (Box 17)
      - Signal School notebooks, 1942 (Box 18)
      - Documents and medals (Box 18)
    - Job applications (Box 18)
    - Advertising and mail order information (Box 18)
    - International Correspondence Schools - business course, 1954-1956 (Box 18)
    - Correspondents and address lists (Box 18)
    - Personal documents (Box 18)
    - Financial material, 2 folders (Box 18)
    - Legal material
      - Estate (Box 18)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 19)
    - Printed material
      - Clippings, 1932-1968; 1974; 2 folders (Box 19)
      - Poetry (Box 19)
      - Theater programs, 3 folders (Box 19)
      - German menus (Box 19)
      - Music scores (Box 19)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 19)
  - Magic show poster (Oversize 4)
  - Photographs (Box 20)
    See also Scrapbooks, below, some of which contain photogaphs.
  - Scarf (Oversize 3)
  - Scrapbooks
    - "Houses", photographs (Box 21)
    - "B. F. Dillon", photographs (Box 21)
    - "George Dillon from 3 mo's old through early maturity", photographs (Box 21)
    - "George W. Hill (1845-1918)", photographs (Box 21)
    - "Relatives", photographs (Box 21)